<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Malcolm Barrett</title>
    <link>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Malcolm Barrett</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Malcolm Barrett</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:16:29 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>R Packages</title>
      <link>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/rpackages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:16:29 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/rpackages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My R Packages are currently available on &lt;a href=&#34;//github.com/malcolmbarrett&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;, and I will be submitting some of them to CRAN soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAG analysis and visualization&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;ggdag&lt;/code&gt;, a package for working with directed acyclic graphs in &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; and built on top of &lt;code&gt;dagitty&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;ggdag&lt;/code&gt; focuses on working with selection bias, confounding, and selecting the right variables to adjust for in an analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Publication-quality tables&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;mable&lt;/code&gt;, a package influenced by &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; and built on top of &lt;code&gt;knitr::kable()&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;kableExtra&lt;/code&gt; to produce fluid, easy-to-build tables for &lt;code&gt;RMarkdown&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working with confounders&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;confoundr&lt;/code&gt;, a package for detecting and visualizing confounding in observational studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visualization for meta-analyses&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;code&gt;ggmeta&lt;/code&gt;, including &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; functionality for forest plots, funnel plots, and influence plots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods in Epidemiology</title>
      <link>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:16:12 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I entered epidemiology because I felt my talented clinical collegues needed help doing their studies well. My research in methodology focuses on bringing first princples in epidemiology to applied analysis. At a certain point in my training, I stopped being able to find answers to my questions about bias, so I started to answer them myself. This work has focused in particular on working with confounding and selection bias.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer</title>
      <link>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:14:36 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of my work in cancer has focused on cancer symptoms and distress that comes from it. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;ve had an interest in pain for many years. I also recently collaborated with colleagues on a meta-analysis of the relationship between cervical cancer and IUD use. I&amp;rsquo;ve used a variety of techniques for these studies, including multi-level models, Bayesian techniques, and predictive modeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Follow-Up Eye Care</title>
      <link>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/predicting_fu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:10:58 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/predicting_fu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Follow-up care is an important issue in long-term eye and vision health. Previous work on the Los Angeles Latino Eye Study and the Chinese American Eye Study have addressed this issue from a cross-sectional perspective, but the African American Eye Disease study is the first of these three to collect data on follow-up care within the first year of the study. In addition to the Health Behavior Model, we&amp;rsquo;re applying a novel model based on psychosocial factors using structural equation modeling, as well as machine learning techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vision and Quality of Life</title>
      <link>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/vision_qol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 14:06:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/auctioner-barnaby-12232.netlify.com/project/vision_qol/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vision loss affects everyday life. Much of my work is on clarifying that effect, particularly between visual acuity and vision-related quality of life (VRQOL). Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on several projects that contribute to the psychometric validity of popular scales for measuring VRQOL. This work is based on data from three large, population-based cohorts in Southern California: The Los Angeles Latino Eye Study, the Chinese American Eye Study, and the African American Eye Study. In addition to classical psychometric techniques, I also apply item response theory and other latent variable models to improve the accuracy of these measures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
